J. Cheyenne Hohman

she/they | j.cheyenne.hohman@gmail.com | +1 (270) 320-5788 | Lexington, KY | linkedin.com/in/cheyennehohman

PROFILE STATEMENT

Cheyenne is a patient, creative and skilled web developer, human switchboard, and brings killer research skills to the table. Her passions include connecting people to resources they need, leveraging her skills in creative ways, and being a team player.

SKILL SETS

- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, SQL, Bootstrap
- Productivity: Microsoft/Apple/Google Suite, Asana, Slack, Trello
- Media: Audition, Photoshop, Premiere, Canva, Reaper, Rekordbox
- Library: Alma/Primo, SIRSI, Biblionix Apollo, Voyager, OCLC, OER, MARC, Creative Commons & Copyright
- Workplace: DEI, Community Management, Digital Collections, Project Management, Training, Teaching

EXPERIENCE

Medical Center Library, University of Kentucky

Oct 2021 - Aug 2022

Library Technician Senior

Lexington, KY

- Assisted students, faculty and community library users with checkout, reservations, ILL and database access
- Developed, reviewed, populated and maintained LibGuide content for College of Dentistry
- Supervised student workers (up to three per shift); scheduled, interviewed and trained new hires
- EDI Committee member; Search Committee participant; Panel interviewer

Library & Academic Resource Center, LA Valley College

Apr 2019 – Sep 2021

Library Technician

Los Angeles, CA

- Provided research services in person and remotely via LibAnswers, email and phone
- Copy-cataloged new items and prepared materials for circulation; assessed, weeded and recycled items
- Supervised & trained student workers; co-authored Student Policy Guide
- Revitalized LibGuides for Open Educational Resources, ADA Compliance and Covid-19 resources

Free Music Archive, WFMU

Oct 2014 – Dec 2018

Director

Jersey City, NJ

- Curated and maintained digital collection of 130,000 recordings, accompanying images, text and metadata
- Produced and hosted podcasts: Radio Free Culture (42 episodes) and FMA Listening Party (70 episodes)
- Authored blogs, album reviews, FAQs and monthly email newsletters to more than 10,000 subscribers
- Secured grants from National Endowment for the Arts totaling \$95,000; raised \$45,000 in donations
- Managed and hired tech staff, volunteers, interns and contract employees for special projects
- Presented about FMA at Internet Archive's Public Domain Day Celebration (2019), Creative Commons Global Summit (2017), WPRB Princeton (2016), MIT Music Hackathon (2014)

College of Arts & Sciences, University of Kentucky

Apr 2010 - Oct 2014

Social Media and Audio Production Team Lead

Lexington, KY

- Originated podcast, audio syndication and social media workflows; published more than 400 podcasts
- Supervised team of student employees to manage social media in Spanish, Chinese and English
- Advised 36 University departments and programs in social media, audio production and best practices
- Received A&S Employee of the Year Award (2013), selected to serve on Culture Committee

EDUCATION

Commonwealth Coders, 2022University of Kentucky, 2011Western Ky University, 2006Front End Web Developer:Master of Science:Bachelor of Arts:Certification (expected Dec 2022)Library & Information Science (4.0)Cultural Anthropology (3.85)